Learn about stack operations, and we all learn about the push method.
Adds an element to adding an element to the top of the stack is called bush.
So consider a stack here.
We have three elements one, two and three.
I need to insert this element into that stack.
So the first element that would be pushed is one.
So I insert one inside the stack.
I push two inside the stack and I push a three into the stack.
OK.
This is how we push, how we insert data and elements into the stack.
Let's consider that code behind pushing data into the stack.
We start by creating intégré size and we define the size defined size.
If what the three if you want and tap equal to minus one.
Then we create a method called bush.
It took into the perimeter.
And Val, so the Val is a valuable or argument that would be added after every time we make Bush so.
If top equal, equal to size minus one, then print stack is full.
Else increase, stop and make the array at the top position equal to VAT, so you are inserting that
element at the top of the stack.
OK, let's see if we push 100, we execute this method the first time.
So push 100, it would execute it and insert it into the element array equal to zero.
Because we, according to this method, we start the from the array at index of top.
So at index stop, it's equal minus one and we have increased the minus one plus one.
It is equal to zero for two that we have increased the top at first and then we have used it as an index
of the array equal to value.
So we assign the van into that at a position equal to zero.
Then we execute push 200.
So push 200 up equal equal to size no minus size minus one no.
So we can insert that.
Otherwise, it will increase by one.
So drop now is equal to one because zero plus one is equal to one.
And we insert 200.
Again, we push 300.
The top is increased by one and 300 has been pushed correctly at a rate equal to two.
If we put push 400, it will not occurs because we are exceeding that equal equal to size minus one
and it will print stack is full.
OK.
Now, let's again make our review what we have done.
We have a curse or or a.
A indicator it's equal to top, and it is minus one because it's empty, we have executed Bush 100,
so we have added 100 and we increased the top by one.
Then we have moved and increased and we have pushed 200 into the stack.
So we increase the top by one.
And now it indicates that up one, which is the level one at a rate equal index one is equal to that
DUP of this stack.
If we insert Bush can't push 300 again, we are executing that increase of DUP by one and we have inserting
300 into our day do so these basic complexity or this time complexity of this operation.
Well, of course, the worst case is equal of one, and the best case is of one.
Yes, you heard here correctly.
OK.
Why?
Because if you are pushing data, we are just increase and that we are just increasing that top index
by one and we assign that.
Are they at index, at exponent position, at a specific position with a current variable or a specific
variable?
So we are just assigning the variables increasing the variable and we are not looping through all the
elements of the stack, like in linked list or an array.
So this is why a stack have a big advantage and making such things such operations.
OK.
So again, it's time complexity would be of of one.
And the worst case and in the best.